Before you die, you see
The Ring is a horror, mystery film directed by Gore Verbinski.
Rachel Keller is a journalist investigating a videotape
that may have killed four teenagers.
There is an urban legend about this tape: the viewer
will die seven days after watching it.
Rachel tracks down the video...
and watches it.
Now she has just seven days to unravel the mystery of the
Ring so she can save herself and her son.
Rachel Keller, played by Naomi Watts.
Noah Clay, played by Martin Henderson.
Aidan Keller, played by David Dorfman.
Richard Morgan, played by Brian Cox.
Dr. Grasnik, played by Jane Alexander.
Ruth Embry, played by Lindsay Frost.
The Ring is a 2002 American supernatural horror film directed by Gore Verbinski, written by Ehren
Kruger, and starring Naomi Watts, Martin Henderson, David Dorfman, and Brian Cox.
The film follows Rachel Keller, a journalist who discovers a cursed VHS
tape that causes its viewers to die seven days later.
It is the first installment in the American Ring series and a remake of the 1998
Japanese film, itself based on the 1991 novel by Koji Suzuki.
The Ring was theatrically released in the United States by DreamWorks Pictures
on October 18, 2002, to mixed-to-positive reviews from critics.
The film grossed $249.3 million worldwide and won Best Horror Film and
Best Actress (for Watts) at the 29th Saturn Awards.
The success of The Ring inspired American remakes of several other Asian and
Japanese horror films, including The Grudge (2004) and Dark Water (2005).
The film explores themes of journalist, island,
drowning, investigation, supernatural.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.